<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acesubido</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://acesubido.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://acesubido.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 03:05:13 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 03:05:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Napkin math: Owning a yacht</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I used to do the Daily UI challenge, I worked on a challenge where I designed a yacht chartering app:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/napkin-app.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before making that design, I had to do research first:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you make a yacht?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How were they sold? (brokering, direct sales, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What brands are popular?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What market do they serve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much is the maintenance cost?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I didn’t learn that, the end design would look so out of touch and unconvincing. As I dove deeper, I found my Youtube feed immersed with yacht related videos. I learned how:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yacht maintenance, as a rule of thumb, usually costs ~10% of its boat value per year. So if you have a 5MUSD yacht, expect 500kUSD/year in costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a fast depreciating asset (10% p.a.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People buy yachts for fun.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you rent out a yacht, that’s called “chartering”. Charter price isn’t determined alone on how good the yacht is. The food, service and crew also contributes to this. Crew should be top notch, polite, can communicate clearly and be good at service.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To fully book your yacht, you’ll need to market a specific niche. You can market your yacht for snorkeling, or water sports like jet skiing and kite surfing. Some yachts are marketed for scuba diving, and others are just meant for slow cruises and island hopping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Italian and Turkish ship building brands are super popular.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monaco is the super yacht capital of the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Online Yacht listings are usually outdated, so you’ll need a yacht broker to find a yacht, and a yacht surveyor (with an engineering background) to check it out if it’s good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/YachtsForSaleCNI&quot;&gt;Youtube has an excellent channel called “YachtsforSale” that really gets you a sneak peek of the yacht world.&lt;/a&gt;. That same youtube channel, endorsed a website called Yatco.com, despite not being sponsored and being it’s competitor. So I checked it out, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yatco.com/buy-a-yacht/detail/242458/2010-princess-yachts-motor-yacht-main-category/&quot;&gt;I saw this 2.5MUSD yacht&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/napkin-princess-yacht.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the &lt;strong&gt;useless-knowledge-hoarder&lt;/strong&gt; in me just decided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hmmm, since we’ve already binged 1 hour of yacht videos. We’re already here: let’s take another 30 minutes, and do napkin math.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like doing “back of a napkin” math. Maybe because it’s a strategic exercise, and I love strategy games like Starcraft and Dune. It’s also a role-playing exercise, and I love RPG’s:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back-of-the-envelope_calculation&quot;&gt;The defining characteristic of back-of-the-envelope calculations is the use of simplified assumptions. A similar phrase in the U.S. is “back of a napkin”, also used in the business world to describe sketching out a quick, rough idea of a business or product.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound defeatist, but I think I will never live long enough to have money for a 2.5M USD yacht. If I ever do get the money to buy one, by some stroke of luck or genius, my conservative personality will keep me at bay from purchasing one. By all means, I am not an authority on yachts, nor have I owned one, so don’t take this next image as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Business advice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some expert claim&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investment advice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just some random dude having fun with numbers. So here’s what the finances might look like, if you ever bought a 2.5M USD yacht:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/napkin-math-yacht-plan.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charter&lt;/strong&gt; means to rent out your yacht to a group of people for a chartered course (ex: Day trip to Bataan, 4 days in Coron). They’ll have a crew of 6, and they can go island/beach hopping, snorkeling, and paddleboarding, etc. Inclusive of food, drink, and accommodation. The yacht has rooms for 8 people, and 8 berths (sleeping areas).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We want to offer high wages for the crew/chef/waitress to get the best talent. We’re basically offering a private resort in the middle of the sea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To earn more cash during a charter, you can do what hotels and cruise liners do: have a mini-bar that charges extra margin (150PHP for a can of pringles, 100PHP for a can of beer consumed out of the usual dinner service, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Based on the Philippine Port Authority website: to park a boat in the dock, it costs 0.020USD per GRT (internal volume, not ship weight) per day. So if our yacht has a volume of 80 tons, you can park it for 1.6USD/day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At 120 days left for personal use, that’s 4 months worth of personal vacations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll get your 2.5MUSD back (break-even) in 29 years at 67% usage (33% for personal use).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you put your CapEx into bonds, you’d retain your 120M and increase it at the same rate of the yacht’s annual profit. Whereas a yacht is a depreciating asset, around 10% p.a. (5M purchase price, 4.5M the next year, 4.05M the next, and so on). So you if you sold the yacht after 10 years, it might be less than 50% of its value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can even use your CapEx for real-estate, it will win out in the end instead of buying a yacht.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yachts are not a good investment nor a store of value. Based on the napkin math, it’s a money sink. People really buy yachts for fun and love of the sea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For people who can afford a yacht, it’s their way to do family/friends vacations, New Year’s Eve or Christmas Parties. They skip the traffic, having to pay for hotel rooms, beach/island hopping, dining-out or purchasing plane tickets. It might cost the same or a little bit more expensive than spending for a family vacation in Monaco or a cruise in the Carribean, but for the extra price, they get privacy and exclusivity. To put this into perspective for us average people; this is a rich person’s annual travel/vacation budget. It’s their equivalent of your budget for a trip to Bohol, road trip to La Union, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sample travel times: Batangas to Palawan in 7 hours. MNL to HK in 3 days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2.5MUSD yacht is comparable to buying a 5 bedroom home in SF (2.75MUSD in Zillow). Except that a yacht costs a lot to maintain, ~10% of its value per year. There are some cases of non-billionaire yacht owners often living in a simpler home than their yachts. They own a yacht to travel, have fun and occasionally charter out to cover costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A 2.5MUSD yacht has more utility than a Bugatti Chiron sports car (2.75MUSD) or a Mercedes-AMG One (2.5MUSD).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re really into it to for the business you could buy a Sail-type yacht. The capex and fuel costs will definitely be cheaper. Sail yachts usually costs half of a motor-based yacht or less. Catamaran Sail Yachts are comparable to the price of motor-based yachts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s also an upcoming market of solar-diesel hybrid yachts for, what they call, eco-friendly millionaires.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the PH, you can also have locally-made yachts that might be a fraction of what it costs to purchase an Azimut, Sunseeker or AB motor-based yacht.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manny Pacquiao’s 2011 Yacht costed P25M. Willie Revillame has 2 yachts in Subic. Gretchen Barretto also has 2 yachts. Chavit Singson’s P600M super yacht was used to transport Miss World candidates for island-hopping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-september-24-2019&quot;&gt;Update: September 24, 2019&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much research and helpful DM’s in twitter, here’s some stuff I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coron Island Hopping tours are 1,500PHP/head for group tours, for private tours it can go up to 3,750PHP/head. This business plan shows a 3,500PHP/head min 10 pax charter rental rate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I underestimated parking your Yacht, it’s called mooring/berthing. It’s very expensive. GRT is for container ships, not for yachts. For example, yachts berthed on Subic Bay is 15,000/month for members of the club, if you’re not a member, it’s a whopping 45,000/month. So better to get a 250,000 membership, you’ll save more in the long run.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marina’s are the lifeblood of the yachting industry, there you can moor/berth your yacht and: 1.) have your gas filled, 2.) use electricity from the Marina or 3.) have maintenance and repairs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I underestimated fuel consumption. Yacht’s eat a lot of fuel. The previous super yacht would’ve eaten more than what I placed there. With a smaller boat you can learn to conserve fuel and cruise at optimal weather and speed, you can definitely save some cash.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll need to get some sort of basic sea navigation or captaining course before I actually start driving my own boat. I can definitely go to the Philippine Yacht Charter association to take some course and learn about operating a boat in the sea.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In order to offer tours with a “motorized boat”, there’s a bunch of registration and government permits you’ll need to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the new table of finances if you took a smaller yacht:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/napkin-math-small-yacht-plann.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;notes&quot;&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I opted to pick a smaller boat as a starter boat, which means anything under 45ft. The smaller the better for a beginner.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Based on a google search, top brands for yachts right now are Beneteau and Princess yachts. So we can use a Princess V40 or a Beneteau Gran Turismo 40.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I picked Azimut Magellano 43 because of it’s design to be a bluewater cruiser. Hull designed to cut waves instead of skip on top of it, making it a very fuel-efficient hull. The result is it allows you to cruise longer for lesser fuel and have a more stable ship. The downside is the slower max speed due to it’s weight. A second-hand 2013 Magellano 43 goes for 417,500USD. Let’s round it up to 450KUSD for misc expenses in order to get it to the PH.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Based on boat tests, an Azimut Magellano 43 going at 10 knots for 3 hours would eat 33 gallons of fuel. 1 gallon is 194PHP. That’s ~6.5KPHP in fuel expenses. It could be enough to hop islands in Coron.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I opted to have 1 employee (whether part-time or full-time) working to maintain the ship and to even Captain it while I’m not around.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;conclusion-1&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The real problem with a yacht is marketing your yacht and planning where your yacht should be to maximize charters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you hit at least 40% utilization, you’ll get back your 23M PHP in 8 years. At 40% utilization, a 23MPHP yacht wins vs. 23MPHP in 3% bonds. 2.5M PHP/yr from charters vs. 690K PHP/yr from bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can probably lease out your yacht, since you’re part of a yacht club. That’s extra cash. You can also offer day-trips to Corregidor or Subic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can definitely make money if you start with a small boat and be efficient with your fuel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An Azimut Magellano 43 can sleep 6 people. You can definitely offer overnight accomodations comparable to a resort and hire a stewardess to do housekeeping and meals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t exactly know the amount I need to set aside for Marine Hull Insurance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t know if I’m underpaying this crew member. It feels like it though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;yatco.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://news.abs-cbn.com/business/03/26/14/can-you-afford-yacht&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://nolisoli.ph/56149/yachts-philippines-jchua-20190125/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.youtube.com/user/YachtsForSaleCNI - lots of good content about the yacht industry, finances, thought processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2019/09/20/napkin-math-owning-a-yacht.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2019/09/20/napkin-math-owning-a-yacht.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's it like to work from home?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been 8 months since I started working from home. I’m with a company called Bloom Solutions, it’s a fintech startup based in the Philippines. Everyone works remotely, we meet face-to-face once or every other a week. Sometimes a few people meet up together on a coffee shop if some work needs to be tightly done together. Other than that, under normal circumstances, most of the work being punched out is done at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Working from home” certainly has it’s benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-efficiency&quot;&gt;Time efficiency&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most valuable benefit. No more 1 1/2 hour one-way commutes, it saves me 3 hours of being on the road. When it rains, make that 4 hours + 400PHP for getting Uber or Grab. Computing that on a back of the napkin, that’s 15 hours a week spent on the road. Which is 60 hours a month, equivalent to 2.5 days a month. If you compute that over a year, it’s equivalent to 30 days being the road. A month where I could’ve spent somewhere else. I now spend more time with my newborn, help out my wife around the house, exercise, hobbies and time for other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minimal-personal-expenses&quot;&gt;Minimal personal expenses&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No parking expense. No commute expense. No gas expense. No “lunch money” expense. Cook food and eat at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;work-not-scoped-to-location&quot;&gt;Work not scoped to location&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go out of the country, go to Tagaytay, go to a beach. It’s all okay, just sync timezones and schedules with the team and make sure that you have no client-facing meetings scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;flexible-schedule&quot;&gt;Flexible schedule&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as I sync with the team and not miss out any important meetings, I can do errands and still put out the work needed. Gone are the days that you’ll have to take a leave to get your VISA or Driver’s License.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;environment-fosters-tangible-results-for-creativesknowledge-workers&quot;&gt;Environment fosters tangible results for Creatives/Knowledge-workers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work from home can be one of those ways to leave little place for programmers to operate in a “body shop” mentality. “Body shop” mentality is a certain mindset where “number of hours being inside the office” is the subconscious metric to measure productivity. Working from home however can provide a setup for people to produce tangible value instead of just waiting for 5pm to arrive. Most people get this feeling that when co-workers are around, you subconsciously feel the need to make it look like you’re always working on something. Always. Always working on something. Typing something. Boss is around? Display that busy IDE. Make random meetings. When you’re working at home, you’re by yourself, it’s just between you and that task list. Just get those done. Sit down, write down the details of what you’re working on, work on a task, ship it, and check that task off the list. Make sure your co-workers can pick up, understand what you wrote, see what’s done and what’s not. Otherwise, nothing will happen, and the company will feel the missing pieces of the work coming from you. Take note that this isn’t applicable to certain industries, and culture dictates how people operate in a self-sustaining manner more than a “remote work” setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;productive-meetings&quot;&gt;Productive meetings&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meetings revolve around strategy, direction, and design decisions. No 1-hour meeting discussing status updates or doing follow ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disadvantages&quot;&gt;Disadvantages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it certainly has it’s disadvantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;distraction-from-friends-and-relatives&quot;&gt;Distraction from Friends and Relatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When friends and relatives are visiting, this is how it usually goes when my wife mentions to them I work from home: “Oh! He works from home? That sounds great! Hey Ace, how’s working from home? Anyway, have you watched the new season of Stranger Things?”. “Umm, it’s great!”. As much as I want not to offend you, please let me focus. This applies to people in the office, the difference with working from home is: the people around you aren’t working. Your lack of interactivity would sometimes come across wrongly to relatives and friends. To some, because you’re in your PJ’s, it doesn’t have much visual weight as someone in the office, you may come across as someone being available for chit-chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; - Smile and gently tell them that you’re currently working and they won’t bother you as much instead of just deflecting their chit chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blurring-lines-between-life-and-work&quot;&gt;Blurring Lines between Life and Work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first few weeks, you wouldn’t know that it’s already at the weekend. Life and work are blurred together. I try to place some distance between them. Before I face my laptop, I take a bath, brush my teeth, wear something else aside from my PJ’s, have my breakfast and then “go” to work. Which involves me going a place in the house where my “office chair” and “table” resides. Then there’s your wife and your children. They know they shouldn’t bother you, so they don’t, but really, they’re there. It’s hard not to talk to Elain and play with Navi when I’m just a tap away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; - We’ve established a group of hours where I can help out in chores or hold/play with Navi. Mainly breakfast, lunch and afternoon snack time. Elain also asks first if I’m on a pomodoro break, or if I’m waiting for CI to pass and build images so that she can ask for help and small favors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;personal-rhythm&quot;&gt;Personal Rhythm&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being at home may make you fall into the temptation of just binge watching videos, surfing social media or looking at HackerNews. Just make sure to maintain discipline, focus and be systematic with how your spend your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution&lt;/strong&gt; - I have my personal time tracker, Harvest, and keep track of what I’m working on and my time. This rhythm gets me going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll probably update this post as time goes by, it’s certainly a life-changing on-going experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2017/11/28/what-s-it-like-to-work-from-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2017/11/28/what-s-it-like-to-work-from-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Encountering Production Bugs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I encountered some features that I engineered which broke in production, it kept me on my toes, but it was worth it to ship the feature properly. A little collection of things I noted down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time pressure is real. Writing something to make something work is different from writing to make it trustworthy, balance them both by keeping the feature scope to be smaller relative to the feature requirement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you encounter a bug, don’t just fix it and it’s unit test, write an integration test for it too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When using Ruby, you might be tempted to metaprogram a lot of stuff to make things lean, don’t abuse it keep things readable, not too verbose but understandable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t abuse dynamic typing and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.try&lt;/code&gt; you might get hurt with nil classes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A very big no no when something is silently failing. Make sure error handling is top notch, especially for background workers. Lift errors up as much as you can to the user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2017/05/29/encountering-production-bugs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2017/05/29/encountering-production-bugs.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Improving our WiFi at home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’m in the process of trying to get the best performance out of our internet setup at home. I’ve worked with Network Architects and ansible’d network configurations for large Hadoop clusters that transfer terabytes, but sadly, I haven’t sat down and fixed our internet at home. I’m a software engineer, and no means a hardcore Cisco Certified Network Engineer, so I decided to sit on this problem and try to improve our situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have slow internet, you can’t just keep throwing money at the problem by upgrading your ISP subscription. You’ll have to check off problems one by one. For me, I sat down and thought: I’ll have to start by improving what I can improve on my side. Which means, the WiFi network within our home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give a short background, our current internet setup at home looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ourwifisetup.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone probably has this simple setup, unless you have a mansion and you need to cover every inch of your house, including your garden and pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I open up terminals and do some &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;iperf&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nc&lt;/code&gt; tests. Initial results revealed that network between 2 local IP addresses in our network is both slow and experiences packet loss. In layman’s terms: our wifi coverage and network throughput generally suck. Beyond the terminal, it’s pretty apparent. A LAN game of “Starcraft: Brood War” between 2 laptops connected on the same network via Wifi, to the same router, is pretty laggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it’s time to really improve our WiFi coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-we-bought-and-what-we-will-buy&quot;&gt;What we bought and what we will buy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the earlier diagram, “Our Wifi Router” and “Our Repeater” we’re bought at PC Express. The router and repeater we have are very old Linksys models, RE1000 for the Repeater and WRT120 for the router. RE1000 was purchased around 2012 and the WRT120N was purchased around 2010. We plan to buy new ones, but should be under a specific budget: 8,000PHP for a router, and 8,000PHP for a repeater. I know that sounds a lot, but I’m currently working from home and would need the internet at our house really worked up. What we plan to buy are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-the-router-we-chose-the-tp-link-archer-c7-v2&quot;&gt;For the router we chose the TP-Link Archer C7 V2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ourwifisetup-archer-c7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thewirecutter.com/reviews/best-wi-fi-router/&quot;&gt;An extensive review was made on it&lt;/a&gt; and it’s pretty cheap compared to the other options. It’s also tested against a multi-room house like ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-the-repeater-we-chose-the-tp-link-re580d-wifi-extender&quot;&gt;For the repeater we chose the TP-Link RE580D WiFi Extender&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ourwifisetup-re580d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for a counterpart to the router, it seems that Netgear Nighthawk EX7000 or EX6200 takes the cake. But there’s no way to purchase it conveniently here in the Philippines, so I came across this TP-Link extender, and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tomsguide.com/us/best-wifi-extenders,review-2225.html&quot;&gt;review’s are good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;optimizing-the-network&quot;&gt;Optimizing the Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before we purchase this, I’ll have to optimize our network first and do a benchmark. Here’s what I found out about tinkering with our routers and such:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-the-main-router&quot;&gt;For The Main Router&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depending on your ISP, it’s best to set some DNS Servers on the main router. Google (8.8.8.8 and 8.8.4.4) and OpenDNS Servers (208.67.222.222 and 208.67.220.220) are best. Personally, we use PLDT, so I leave this blank. Using Google or OpenDNS as your DNS Servers seems a good idea but not for us. Based on my experience, for PLDT MyDSL Home connections, PLDT optimizes their connections with PLDT’s DNS Servers. Otherwise, you get bogged down by a lot of “Resolving Host” issues. A minor compromise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On “Channel Width”, as much as possible, set it to 40MHz wide channels. You get the best peformance out of your router. But only use this if all of your devices support 802.11n. Otherwise, just use the 20MHz default.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set your “Standard Channel” to some other channel that’s not common with other Wifi Signals in your area. Use a Wifi scanner (install one in your Android phone) and scan your area for other Wifi signals, there you’ll see the channels their using. If you set your “Standard Channel” to something uncommon, you’ll get better reception and network performance since you’re in a “less” crowded channel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-repeaters&quot;&gt;For Repeaters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anything infrastructure related should have Static IP’s. So if you have Wifi repeaters in your home, set a static IP for them in the main router. This’ll prevent them from having to look for an IP everytime they’re booted, or their connection needs to be renewed. It makes resolving hosts faster as well. For Linksys routers just click on “DHCP Reservation” and look for your repeater repeater listed there. Check it and reserve an IP for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Channel Width should be set as the same with the main router it’s connected to.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double check that your repeater is also set on the same encryption as the main router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-devices&quot;&gt;For devices&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unless you’re doing something out of the norm, like remote tunnels to datacenters, don’t set your DNS servers. Let the router supply them for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re using Google Chrome, flush your DNS cache. You can do this by typing this address at the chrome address bar: chrome://net-internals/#dns . Then click ‘Clear Host Cache’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-do-you-use-to-test-internet-speeds&quot;&gt;“What do you use to test internet speeds?”&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Netflix’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://fast.com&quot;&gt;fast.com&lt;/a&gt; to be much better in terms of UX and sensible defaults. It tries to simulate a download from Netflix’s Global CDN, which is probably the use case for most of the sites I visit (google, youtube, reddit, facebook, hacker news, github, etc.). &lt;a href=&quot;https://speedtest.net&quot;&gt;Speedtest.net&lt;/a&gt; is great if you’re testing specifics, but for the majority of the use-cases, it’s too granular. The defaults assume I’m connecting to a local server. My browser is downloading a Dota 2 video from Youtube.com and my laptop is pushing a repo at Github.com, I’m not accessing some web page in Globe Makati.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bet there are a lot more settings I’ve missed, and this is a work in progress. I’ll post a part 2 once we get the new hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2017/05/21/improving-our-wifi-at-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2017/05/21/improving-our-wifi-at-home.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Speed up Ruby app bootup time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I frequently work with a large ruby application, and whenever I run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rspec path/to/single_unit_test.rb&lt;/code&gt; in a Rails application, it takes 2-3 seconds before the test starts. This is because of the amount of source files that are involved in the application. Fortunately, Shopify released a gem called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shopify/bootsnap&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bootsnap&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The short story: it speeds up ruby app boot time. Useful for large monolithic applications. Ruby apps slow down if you &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;require&lt;/code&gt; a lot of source files, so it speeds things up by doing applying some optimizations (compilation caching, YAML optimzations, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://engineering.shopify.com/235340559-bootsnap-optimizing-ruby-app-boot-time&quot;&gt;The long explanation, found here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplest setup for a Rails 5.1.1 app (as of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bootsnap 0.2.14&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# Gemfile&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;gem&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'bootsnap'&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;# bin/bundle&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'bootsnap'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Bootsnap&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;setup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;cache_dir: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'tmp/cache'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;development_mode: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;ENV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'RAILS_ENV'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'development'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;load_path_cache: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;autoload_paths_cache: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;disable_trace: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;compile_cache_iseq: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;compile_cache_yaml: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kp&quot;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It plays nicely with spring by speeding up the pre-fork and post-fork. Definitely a gem worth watching out for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2017/05/20/speed-up-ruby-app-bootup-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2017/05/20/speed-up-ruby-app-bootup-time.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BigDecimal vs. Float for anything related to finance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are countless blog posts and stack overflow explanations about this, figured I need to write this little note for myself. To start things off, check this example of computing PHPKRW using hypothetical gold as a go-between:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;require &quot;bigdecimal&quot;

# Float
php_gold_float = 0.00001144792038
gold_krw_float = 1962165.41

php_krw_float = php_gold_float * gold_krw_float

puts &quot;#{php_krw_float.class} #{php_krw_float}&quot;

# Big Decimal
php_gold_bd = BigDecimal.new(&quot;0.00001144792038&quot;)
gold_krw_bd = BigDecimal.new(&quot;1962165.41&quot;)

php_krw_bd = php_gold_bd * gold_krw_bd

puts &quot;#{php_krw_bd.class} #{php_krw_bd.to_s('F')}&quot;

# Output
Float 22.462713386070057
BigDecimal 22.4627133860700558
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thats-odd-its-rounded-up-or-something-why-does-this-happen&quot;&gt;That’s odd, it’s rounded up? Or something? Why does this happen?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long version, read up on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_floating_point#IEEE_754-2008&quot;&gt;IEEE specification to define floats&lt;/a&gt;. Short version: it stores a sign, a fraction and an exponent to represent a Float. It’s a scientific notation for binary, because of that it’s impossible to store exact numbers and decimal in Float.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a bank, or if you’re supporting accounting software, or just computing compounding interests, you could potentially miscalculate thousands down the line when using Float for computing. So, make sure to use BigDecimal when you’re dealing with anything that requires a high-degree of “sureness”. With Ruby/Rails, you can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:decimal&lt;/code&gt; for columns containing this type of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money, accounting, computing compounding interests = needs high precision, then use BigDecimal. Other than that, just use float.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some gotcha’s: With Ruby/Rails, when rendering an object with BigDecimal attributes as JSON, it will render the numbers as a String, instead of a Float. Part of the reasoning behind this change could be found in this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rails/rails/issues/25017&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2017/05/16/bigdecimal-vs-float-for-anything-related-to-finance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2017/05/16/bigdecimal-vs-float-for-anything-related-to-finance.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thoughts on the elections - everyone needs a savior</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Elections is coming, and to be honest, I had to install a chrome filter to block out my feeds from certain keywords. Visiting CNN Philippines and Rappler, the past few weeks had me realizing one thing: everyone needs a savior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;israelites&quot;&gt;Israelites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look closely, in the Bible, the Israelites went through a bunch of phases in their history as a nation 1) where they had leaders and 2) where they didn’t have leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old Testament depicts a nation of not having a leader, then transitioning to having Moses and Joshua as a leader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Israelites then went through a phase of having a bunch of Judges leading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They clamored at Samuel because they wanted a king, it would make things perfect and in order if they would get one, so they get King Saul, then King David and King Solomon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Israelites liked King Saul because at that time, their main issue was the imminent threat of invaders. King Saul was the human embodiment of might, charisma and stability they could run under, that’s why they liked him. It turns out one of their best periods as a nation was with someone opposite of his stature: David.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Psalms sing about a relationship with God&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Majority of the Old Testament depicts being under rule of invaders.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shadrach, Meshach and Abednego lived under King Nebuchadnezzar’s rule.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Testament depicts a society where they all wanted a king that would fix their current problem: being ruled over by the Romans. Instead they get Jesus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite having a king, no king, prophets, or no prophets there was a common theme: once their hearts turned away from God it lead to ruin, poverty, shame and exile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-citizens&quot;&gt;Better citizens&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see it in social media and the news across the country: the cries of change and the cries for rescue. The Filipinos and the Israelites of the Bible share a common thing: we want a savior, we want change, we want rescue, and we think if we get a better king/president it will fix everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it won’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me get straight to the point: the Philippines doesn’t need a better president, it needs better citizens. No matter how good our president is, if our hearts are not aligned with God, then the things we value are skewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will objectify women&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will do shortcuts (fixers, not falling in line properly, spitting on the ground, throwing trash everywhere)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will be selfish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will not trust authority&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will not respect our followers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will be easily bought&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will curse our fellow man (putting down others, crab-mentality)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will envy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will murder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will steal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will be insecure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will not care about being competent (excellence in service, research and production)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We will not respect and learn about God’s creation (science, education, environmentalism)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The list goes on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The saying “change is coming” is true, but it can come tomorrow, or right now; because change should come from within you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who wins in the coming elections, the president does not hold your future, God does.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2016/05/03/election-revelation-everyone-needs-a-savior.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2016/05/03/election-revelation-everyone-needs-a-savior.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My useful secret projects and business ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little note:&lt;/em&gt; Developers are craftsmen. They build things for a living. As a side effect, they’ll try to build a lot of things that they need or want for themselves. A handful, to an extent, dreams to run a business around what they’ve built. Most fail, not because they didn’t have enough time or it didn’t have enough features (trust me, we can build a lot of unwanted features). The main reason most fail is no one knows about the things they’ve built in the first place, and no one uses them, even themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how most developers feel, because I’m a developer myself. This is more of a note to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers tend to think of side projects as a way to “passive income”. In reality, there’s no such thing as true “passive income” except for “investment funds”. At some point you really have to email people, build relationships, go to a bank and sign some stuff. &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot;&gt;It’s actual work. Instead of thinking about building a way to earn “passive income”, reset your mind and think about building a “business”&lt;/a&gt;. It’ll end up as a “business” if you move forward with your side project. As a developer, the difference is that you just have more automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more notes to myself about this topic, but this isn’t the blog post to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Useful secret projects and business ideas”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paradox. Obviously, business ideas aren’t useful since they’re only ideas, secret projects aren’t useful when no one’s using it. Moreover, these little apps and sideprojects will never be “finished”, because “finished” is a vague finish line unless someone uses it. Even then, it’s not “finished” if someone uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to turn a new leaf this year. I had this in my ‘drafts’, but I’ll publish it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/ws&quot;&gt;Being&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/ideas&quot;&gt;inspired&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samsquire/ideas&quot;&gt;by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ideas.html&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://grahamwahlberg.com/business-ideas/&quot;&gt;guys&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve decided to open them all up for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas and projects were born out of my personal frustrations and dreams that have been born after being in the software industry for 5+ years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just message me directly if any of you guys would desperately need any of these. If you’re interested in using some of the stuff that’s already made; we can talk it out so that I can set it up for you. Honestly, most of them have been done by other people/companies. I’ll link some of the ones that I know under each idea/project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developers-toolsapplications&quot;&gt;Developers Tools/Applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;endpointy&quot;&gt;Endpointy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static websites need to have some semblance of functionality where people can give their email, or fill up a form. Endpointy gives you a POST endpoint for each form in your static websites, you can login and view the things being submitted. Formkeep does a great job at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: around 60-ish% done for an MVP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;softshelf&quot;&gt;Softshelf&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your very own internal app store with an API for integrations in CI/git servers. Self-hosted. For companies that sell software and documents as products. A client portal where you can upload the artifact/release and your clients can download it from there. It also contains links to issue trackers, and other related stuff to the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Need this for work, started it but on halt right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aclys&quot;&gt;Aclys&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experimental attempt to make the smallest in-memory key-value database. A tiny experimental in-memory key/value store on top of Finagle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ace-subido/aclys&quot;&gt;Code is in here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finance&quot;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pouchnote&quot;&gt;Pouchnote&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really small accounting system; an income and expense ledger. Write down income and expense entries like tweeting. It’s a very simple way to keep track of your incomes and expenses. Good for quickly jotting down income and expense entries without thinking excel sheet cell computations and following formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Beta. 100% working, &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/ace-subido/pouchnote&quot;&gt;screenshots and code in my Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quoteplate&quot;&gt;Quoteplate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templated Word/PDF Documents. Let your salesmen and biz dev guys keep selling instead of worrying about keeping a document formatted. You know that one document they keep copy-pasting and they just change certain words and items in it? And they keep resending it to someone? Quoteplate was envisioned to be integrated to e-signatures, inventory, tables and contacts to make that way way easier. I worked on this with my friend Eric Wong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coinjobs&quot;&gt;Coinjobs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job Board for the Cryptocurrency industry. Got in a little too late, since there were a lot of other job boards already popping around that time: coinality, bitgigs, bitcoinjobfair to name a few. I worked on this with my friend Ramon Tayag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinjobs.link&quot;&gt;coinjobs.link&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html&quot;&gt;Built it, contacted people and companies, traction never came. It was a nice try. Code is still good to go.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;philippine-mutual-funds-api&quot;&gt;Philippine Mutual Funds API&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to compare Philippine Mutual Funds and categorize them easily. I thought of building an API endpoint for Philippine Mutual Funds, scrape data from public websites and make them available in an API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: In the backburner&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;storage&quot;&gt;Storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;filemailup&quot;&gt;Filemailup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat for files. Open up your email account, and make an email, attach your files, and send your email to up@save.filemailup.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would get an email reply from Filemailup with a link to a web page where you can get and share your files to people. If you wrote something in the subject and wrote something in the email, that would be displayed too. After 24 hours, that page gets deleted, because frankly you won’t need it anymore if you’re sending it by email anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/2013/11/03/filemailup-share-files-from-your-email.html&quot;&gt;Done in 2013. Beta stage. 100% working, code in Bitbucket, got 8 users, but barely had any activity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;managed-data-storage-for-photographers-videographers-and-etc&quot;&gt;Managed Data Storage for Photographers, Videographers and etc.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to archive some data? We’ll send you a hard drive, fill it with stuff and we’ll pick it up and store it for you. Access thumbnails, and other short snippets of the data (metadata) via cloud. Need to download a lot of your stuff? We’ll ship you back a hard drive within the day. Internet is bad in the Philippines. Either upload or set up your own NAS and manage your drives. We’ll handle the latter option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a person handing you a hard drive has better bandwidth and latency than sending it over the wire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saasmobile-apps&quot;&gt;SaaS/Mobile Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;balikan&quot;&gt;Balikan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple bookmarking service that lets you make your own link aggregator out of your bookmarks. Save links into your own archive. They get scraped so even if the website goes down you have a personal copy of the web page. Organize them into reading lists. Share reading lists to your friends, family and officemates. Spotify for your bookmarks. Also worked on this with Eric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Beta stage. Got 5 users to test it. Went into a revamp after feedback, halted it because I got busy with work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;game-knights&quot;&gt;Game Knights&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalistic leaderboards for those who host Game Nights. Snap a photo of the winner for that nights’ game night, type in the game that he played, write a short description about how he won and how many points. Revenue model? Get game publishers to advertise. Provide “Pro accounts” for board game pubs and card game/hobby shops such as Ludo, Neutral Grounds and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;yrsay&quot;&gt;yrsay&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay what you want for digital goods. Upload your song, art, software, ebook and get a link. Share that link with people, they’ll pay you in Bitcoin and they get the download. Close alternatives are: Gumroad and Plasso.co. Worked on this with Ramon Tayag as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Ramon got it up and running, I mostly did the design. I’ll try to get this running to provide screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;simple-restaurant-reservations&quot;&gt;Simple Restaurant Reservations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ticketbase for Restaurants (in terms of UI/UX). Instead of selling tickets, it takes reservations for restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cyclonesign&quot;&gt;Cyclonesign&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://stormpulse.com&quot;&gt;Stormpulse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://riskpulse.com&quot;&gt;Riskpulse&lt;/a&gt;, but bringing it in the Philippines. The Philippines gets hit with over 20 storms per year, we lose a lot of money because of this. Enables companies to be at the same level of proactiveness as PAGASA and government agencies. Plot out your physical assets and routes in the Philippines using a map, set alerts for wind levels and temperature, person in-charge/cargo drivers gets SMS warnings when something reaches the threshold. B2B model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: I developed large parts of this for a long time. Indexed and scraped a truckload of data from various international and national government weather sites. Wasn’t a fan of private API’s, government data for storms were more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;report-for-tasks-done-self-hosted-idonethis&quot;&gt;Report For Tasks Done: Self-hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://idonethis.com/&quot;&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple Team Performance Management in contrast of Project Management. Twitter/Dribbble like experience asking you about what you worked and what you accomplished on. You can only post once a day. Automatically builds a view of what your entire team has accomplished during a project using these tweets. Celebrate small wins and keep morale up. You can also get what you’ve accomplished during your tenure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minutes-of-the-meeting-markup&quot;&gt;Minutes of the Meeting markup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the environment where I sometimes get to be faced with clients. I want to have a markup similar as Markdown, but specifically targetting the minutes of the meeting. More attention to the meeting, less attention to writing it all down and formatting it. Write Frontmatter, write it in a specified format, enter something in your command line, and it gets sent to all the contacts in the Frontmatter. Complete with actionable items and main highlights of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;services&quot;&gt;Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;uber-for-house-services&quot;&gt;Uber for House Services&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a plumbing problem? Snap a photo, make a few descriptions, select “Plumbing Service”, Service providers try to bid on it. It’s essentially a mobile application where you can easily get services for your home. Fortunately gawin.ph is a prime example of this, and I’m excited to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creative-services-friends&quot;&gt;Creative Services Friends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need a hip hop dance instructor? An events host? An graphic artist? A videographer? A photographer? An events coordinator? Baker? Acting coach? My group of friends offer these services. The app allows you to easily get their services. Just like ‘Uber for House Services’, but this targets creatives. The value? Curation. The app can be used to set up your own “Creative Services Group” with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it, I’ll keep updating this very same list. I’ll probably permalink this in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/about&quot;&gt;“about/contact”&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Hey some of these are great! Wouldn’t someone steal these? Why would you give that away?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some good reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LechKaniuk/status/683811288842133505&quot;&gt;You should be more afraid if no one wants to copy you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10944972&quot;&gt;“Idea’s are like blank books. Unless you have passion for the idea, you are not going to fill in the 400 blank pages with the details.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-1-blog-series/ideas-are-cheap-execution-is-worth-millions-e203efbcaa49&quot;&gt;Idea’s are cheap, execution is worth millions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It’s a disease to think that a great idea is 90 percent of the work. The problem with that is that there’s just a tremendous amount of craftsmanship in between a great idea and a great product” - Steve Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook, Google+, MySpace, Friendster, Orkut all had the same idea. But execution and design is what matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10942823&quot;&gt;it’s been two years now, and nobody has stolen any of the ideas. It could just be that my ideas suck, but I suspect that the worry of people stealing ideas is nothing to worry about for any of us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be honest, each one of these ideas takes about 5-10 years to work on it and make it fruitful. At which point, either it stays true to the original idea throughout or evolves into something totally different. I only have one lifetime and I won’t have time to take on every one of these things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the idea of “stealing” is a “pessimists” view. Viewing this in an optimistic perspective, I may actually get in contact with people who definitely need someone to technically implement any of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2016/01/21/my-useful-secret-projects-and-business-ideas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2016/01/21/my-useful-secret-projects-and-business-ideas.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How can executives/business guys 'appreciate' Big Data?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I get that question from some of my officemates. How can people appreciate “Big Data Technologies”. Is there a demo to make people appreciate “Big Data” or “Hadoop”? How can we sell “Data Lakes vs Data Warehouses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s hard to appreciate a piece of technology without knowing what pain it actually solves. Hadoop solves the pain of computing by presenting this conventional way of doing Distributed Computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the term “Big Data” is being passed around too much, it’s getting too abstracted. We need to get a little lower down the chain, closer to real things and tasks entailing “doing Big Data”. As I said before, I feel that “Big Data” is a marketing term thrown for problems/solutions revolving around “Distributed Computing and Storage”, much like how “Cloud” is for “Remote Servers, Services and Applications”. At the tip of these solutions is something called Hadoop. Now, Hadoop is more of a framework, accompanied with a set of libraries to implement that framework. At the current state of the software industry, there’s no single piece of technology that magically translates your data into wonderful visualizations and actionable insights that’s instantly aligned to making your business more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been blinded by technology. We’re so impressed by “Big Data” and all these buzzwords revolving around technology. We forget that technology isn’t meant to replace humans and how we process information, but it was made to complement us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The other buzzword that epitomizes a bias toward substitution is “big data”. Today’s companies have an insatiable appetite for data, mistakenly believeing that more data always creates more value. But big data is usually dumb data. Computers can find patterns that elude humans, but they don’t know how to compare patterns from different sources or how to interpret complex behaviors. Actionable insights can only come from a human analyst (or the kind of generalized artifical intelligence that exists only in science fiction).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We have let ourselves become enchanted by big data only because we exoticize technology. We’re impressed with small feats accomplished by computers alone but we ignore achievements from complementarity because the human contribution makes them less uncanny.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Peter Thiel (Founder of Paypal and Palantir), from “Zero To One”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Data technologies such as Hadoop, HBase, NiFi, Tableau and Spark are tools for Developers and Analysts to make their lives easier. It makes it easier for them to crunch numbers, transform data, and other stuff to make those charts and visualizations the business guys are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s hard to sell them to business guys as some sort of “magic box”. There’s no “demo” where they can instantly “appreciate it” without human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like saying “How can executives/business guys ‘appreciate’ Ruby on Rails?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to sell that to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demos with fancy charts won’t work on most business guys: “Hey, our current IT Team can do that with their databases and BI tools. What’s new?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, “how can executive/business guys ‘appreciate’ Big Data?”. Take this with a grain of salt though, I’m not a biz dev guy: Sell it to their VP of Engineering, their developers, their technical team. Naturally they’ll build great apps and dashboards on top of it. It’ll sell itself to the rest of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: My thoughts written here are not of my employers. These are solely my opinions and they’re not tied to what AGSX stands for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2016/01/21/how-can-executives-appreciate-big-data-technologies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2016/01/21/how-can-executives-appreciate-big-data-technologies.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where to invest my money? I'm 17 years old ....</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A 17-year old asked the Philippine subreddit the following question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m 17 years old (turning 18 on August, 2016), i’m still studying college (my 1st year) and at the same time, doing freelance designing. I earn 20-30k php per month sa designs ko. So far so good naman, kayang i-balance ang study at freelance work.
Been doing this since 2012, thanks to my designs, i was able to buy things i want and i need. Now comes a point na halos ok na ko sa mga meron ako, and iniisip ko kung paano ko ma-save ang pera ko. Wala naman ako alam sa mga investments/stocks/etc dahil ang course ko ay Multimedia Arts. Tried searching online about sa stock market but i dont think i have the knowledge para pasukin yun.
What’s the best way para ma-save ko ang money ko at hindi ako bili ng bili ng mga not-so-important stuff? I don’t want to be broke when i grow up, so i want to save these money :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put together a handy-dandy handbook/guide for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, before anything, remove all debt. Zero out your credit card balance on the things you just bought. “Financial freedom” is only attained when you have no debt. Someone who nets 20-30K PHP per month but doesn’t have debt, has more “financial freedom” than someone who nets 150K PHP yet has a large chunk of debt and lives under stress of knowing they owe someone money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Second, change your mindset in purchases. The best way to save your money is not some list of things to do, but rather, a radical change of mindset: don’t let material possessions define your identity. Define “need to have” and “nice to have”. Ask yourself “what do I value?” whenever you feel you’re about to purchase something stupid. Do you really need a moleskine for mockups? Is buying another cup of Starbucks really that important? Do I really need a new pair of shoes? Get your parents to help you in this. Another set of eyes definitely helps. You’re young, so don’t worry about getting broke and spending your savings, worry about what you’re actually spending your money on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Third, is the most important one, if you do this and #2, you can easily get #4: Change your mindset on the word “investment”. Money is a device to exchange value, it is not a source of wealth, it will run out on you. So, technically, the best “investment” is putting more money on what currently earns you money: your skill. Buy a book from a famous designer, attend FFC, engage the design community and the market, spend more money/time experimenting and working on your own project, instead of doing something else. This mindset will increase how much you earn in amounts that you will not foresee.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I do this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Think of a rich person, one who gained their riches from great skill. If you took away their “businesses”, “investments” and “savings”, they probably won’t have a problem. Sure they’ll get hurt badly, but they can recover from a bankruptcy. The reason is because they’ve invested highly in themselves and are highly skilled. With their skill, they’ve attained a good professional network and they can easily recover from brutal bankruptcies. Their “investments” (stocks/mutual funds/etc.) are just overflow, fruits, of their true investment: their skill.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;On the opposite, research about lottery winners who ironically got bankrupted. Take note: some of them even had “funds and investments”.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you ever got broke, you can confidently get back up due to reputation, discipline in purchases and skill.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fourth, the only time you “invest” or pour money into “investments/funds”, is when income is already overflowing against your expenses. The best gauge for that is when you’ve 1) attained the usual “3-6 months of income as savings” and 2) at least being able to save more than 30-50% of your monthly net. A well-maintained bank account is a sign of debtlessness, discipline in purchases, and overflow. This makes you liquid, allowing you to shift wealth to where you need it (emergencies, travel, skill investment, etc.). It’s the reason why a lot of people over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/personalfinance&quot;&gt;/r/personalfinance&lt;/a&gt; suggests to work on a savings account first.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fifth, after you’ve changed your mindset, proven you can manage your finances with a good bank account, then you can get your hands dirty with “investments” while improving your skill:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Get medical insurance first, your parents will jump for joy when you get this for yourself. Head over to Blue Cross or Medicard. Basic medical coverage from Medicard hover around 8.9K PHP/year (700PHP~ per month).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Get life insurance that also doubles as an investment fund (SunLife is a safe bet, PruLife has nice offerings that has medical coverage infused with it).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lastly, pick an Index Fund. BPI offers the Philippine Equity Index Fund. BDO has this as well. Whichever you like, they both perform very well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ano yung Index Fund?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In much simpler terms: Ever see a picture or a huge chart in the business/finance section of a media website or a newspaper? The one that says “Philippine Stock Exchange Composite Index”? An Index Fund tries to closely follow those numbers. In laymans terms: You give money to a company, say BPI. The company would have fund managers that pick and trade stocks which closely matches the companies in that huge chart. So, when you see that the “Philippine Stock Exchange Composite Index” went up by 2% in one month, you can safely assume that the money you placed in BPI went up at about 1.25%-1.5% for that month as well.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ang daming mga iba pang funds diba? Why an Index Fund? Why not a mutual fund or treasury bills? Ano difference nila?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’ll explain as simple as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Treasury bills are government-based. You give the government money, they turn it into government projects which earns them money, which they use to pay you back with interest. T-bills as they call it are for the paranoid; they’re ultra-safe. Unless the Senate voted to turn itself into a strip club and Malacanang is burning with gasoline, your money is safe from anything else in the world. Besides if it came to that, money might not be important anymore in the Philippines anyway; you’d have to rely on your skill to live or learn farming to feed yourself. However, with the safety, comes a huge cost (minimum is 200K on PNB, returns per year are very small, expect a 10-20 year return)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mutual funds are a pool of money from different people: they hire a professional stock broker or fund manager which trades for them. Mutual funds have higher transaction fees than Index Funds. From a personal experience, only a few mutual funds/companies have beaten or come close to the Index, and the really good ones are pretty expensive and complicated to enter into.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, again, why an Index Fund?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A NYTimes article called the American-based “Vanguard Index Fund” as the “bread-and-butter index fund for the individual”. Index Funds are a gateway to the stock market and opens up your mind about it. It’s “the vanilla ice cream of finance”. They have low transaction fees, they’re easy to understand, doesn’t require much commitment and as “passive” as you make it. They’re not as safe though, when a “market crash” happens, everyone gets pulled down, especially Index Funds. Don’t worry; what goes down usually goes back up, people usually get great returns from Index funds when they hold them for 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you’re not earning millions per year and just starting out on investments, this is your go to.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;BPI Express Online and BDO Online Banking integrates tightly with their index funds. You can easily top up and cash out straight from/to your bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On picking and trading stocks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It actively requires “skill”. Picking and trading stocks is a skillset to be learned. You have to be up to date, and you need to pick your companies well and do your research on them. If you really want to improve on that skill, head over to COL Financial to get a grasp of things. It doesn’t matter if COL is good/not-good based on the opinion of other people, what matters is you get started.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Personally I don’t advise this path, unless you really want to build a career as a really good trader. You’re already good at design, so don’t lose focus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Few reminders: Don’t get arrogant. Don’t be in a hurry to make more money. Don’t be in a hurry. Period. Take time to get better with your work, don’t rush it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://acesubido.net/2015/11/14/where-to-invest-my-money-i-m-17-years-old.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://acesubido.net/2015/11/14/where-to-invest-my-money-i-m-17-years-old.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
