<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acesubido</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://acesubido.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://acesubido.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 17:51:13 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 17:51:13 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My useful secret projects and business ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little note:&lt;/em&gt; Developers are craftsmen. They build things for a living. As a side effect, they’ll try to build a lot of things that they need or want for themselves. A handful, to an extent, dreams to run a business around what they’ve built. Most fail, not because they didn’t have enough time or it didn’t have enough features (trust me, we can build a lot of unwanted features). The main reason most fail is no one knows about the things they’ve built in the first place, and no one uses them, even themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know how most developers feel, because I’m a developer myself. This is more of a note to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers tend to think of side projects as a way to “passive income”. In reality, there’s no such thing as true “passive income” except for “investment funds”. At some point you really have to email people, build relationships, go to a bank and sign some stuff. &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ds.html&quot;&gt;It’s actual work. Instead of thinking about building a way to earn “passive income”, reset your mind and think about building a “business”&lt;/a&gt;. It’ll end up as a “business” if you move forward with your side project. As a developer, the difference is that you just have more automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have more notes to myself about this topic, but this isn’t the blog post to talk about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Useful secret projects and business ideas”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a paradox. Obviously, business ideas aren’t useful since they’re only ideas, secret projects aren’t useful when no one’s using it. Moreover, these little apps and sideprojects will never be “finished”, because “finished” is a vague finish line unless someone uses it. Even then, it’s not “finished” if someone uses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to turn a new leaf this year. I had this in my ‘drafts’, but I’ll publish it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sivers.org/ws&quot;&gt;Being&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/ideas&quot;&gt;inspired&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/samsquire/ideas&quot;&gt;by&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/ideas.html&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://grahamwahlberg.com/business-ideas/&quot;&gt;guys&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve decided to open them all up for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ideas and projects were born out of my personal frustrations and dreams that have been born after being in the software industry for 5+ years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just message me directly if any of you guys would desperately need any of these. If you’re interested in using some of the stuff that’s already made; we can talk it out so that I can set it up for you. Honestly, most of them have been done by other people/companies. I’ll link some of the ones that I know under each idea/project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;developers-toolsapplications&quot;&gt;Developers Tools/Applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;endpointy&quot;&gt;Endpointy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static websites need to have some semblance of functionality where people can give their email, or fill up a form. Endpointy gives you a POST endpoint for each form in your static websites, you can login and view the things being submitted. Formkeep does a great job at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: around 60-ish% done for an MVP&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;softshelf&quot;&gt;Softshelf&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your very own internal app store with an API for integrations in CI/git servers. Self-hosted. For companies that sell software and documents as products. A client portal where you can upload the artifact/release and your clients can download it from there. It also contains links to issue trackers, and other related stuff to the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Need this for work, started it but on halt right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aclys&quot;&gt;Aclys&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experimental attempt to make the smallest in-memory key-value database. A tiny experimental in-memory key/value store on top of Finagle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ace-subido/aclys&quot;&gt;Code is in here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fastscrum&quot;&gt;FastScrum&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of each day/week, receive an email with 3 questions: 1) What did you finish yesterday? 2) What are you going to do today? 3) Anything blocking you from moving forward? You reply and people can see your reply in an in-app dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finance&quot;&gt;Finance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pouchnote&quot;&gt;Pouchnote&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A really small accounting system; an income and expense ledger. Write down income and expense entries like tweeting. It’s a very simple way to keep track of your incomes and expenses. Good for quickly jotting down income and expense entries without thinking excel sheet cell computations and following formats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Beta. 100% working, &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/ace-subido/pouchnote&quot;&gt;screenshots and code in my Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quoteplate&quot;&gt;Quoteplate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templated Word/PDF Documents. Let your salesmen and biz dev guys keep selling instead of worrying about keeping a document formatted. You know that one document they keep copy-pasting and they just change certain words and items in it? And they keep resending it to someone? Quoteplate was envisioned to be integrated to e-signatures, inventory, tables and contacts to make that way way easier. I worked on this with my friend Eric Wong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;coinjobs&quot;&gt;Coinjobs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job Board for the Cryptocurrency industry. Got in a little too late, since there were a lot of other job boards already popping around that time: coinality, bitgigs, bitcoinjobfair to name a few. I worked on this with my friend Ramon Tayag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;http://coinjobs.link&quot;&gt;coinjobs.link&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html&quot;&gt;Built it, contacted people and companies, traction never came. It was a nice try. Code is still good to go.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;storage&quot;&gt;Storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;filemailup&quot;&gt;Filemailup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snapchat for files. Open up your email account, and make an email, attach your files, and send your email to up@save.filemailup.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You would get an email reply from Filemailup with a link to a web page where you can get and share your files to people. If you wrote something in the subject and wrote something in the email, that would be displayed too. After 24 hours, that page gets deleted, because frankly you won’t need it anymore if you’re sending it by email anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/2013/11/03/filemailup-share-files-from-your-email.html&quot;&gt;Done in 2013. Beta stage. 100% working, code in Bitbucket, got 8 users, but barely had any activity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;managed-data-storage-for-photographers-videographers-and-etc&quot;&gt;Managed Data Storage for Photographers, Videographers and etc.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need to archive some data? We’ll send you a hard drive, fill it with stuff and we’ll pick it up and store it for you. Access thumbnails, and other short snippets of the data (metadata) via cloud. Need to download a lot of your stuff? We’ll ship you back a hard drive within the day. Internet is bad in the Philippines. Either upload or set up your own NAS and manage your drives. We’ll handle the latter option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a person handing you a hard drive has better bandwidth and latency than sending it over the wire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;saasmobile-apps&quot;&gt;SaaS/Mobile Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;balikan&quot;&gt;Balikan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple bookmarking service that lets you make your own link aggregator out of your bookmarks. Save links into your own archive. They get scraped so even if the website goes down you have a personal copy of the web page. Organize them into reading lists. Share reading lists to your friends, family and officemates. Spotify for your bookmarks. Also worked on this with Eric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Beta stage. Got 5 users to test it. Went into a revamp after feedback, halted it because I got busy with work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;game-knights&quot;&gt;Game Knights&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalistic leaderboards for those who host Game Nights. Snap a photo of the winner for that nights’ game night, type in the game that he played, write a short description about how he won and how many points. Revenue model? Get game publishers to advertise. Provide “Pro accounts” for board game pubs and card game/hobby shops such as Ludo, Neutral Grounds and the like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;yrsay&quot;&gt;yrsay&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pay what you want for digital goods. Upload your song, art, software, ebook and get a link. Share that link with people, they’ll pay you in Bitcoin and they get the download. Close alternatives are: Gumroad and Plasso.co. Worked on this with Ramon Tayag as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: Ramon got it up and running, I mostly did the design. I’ll try to get this running to provide screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;simple-restaurant-reservations&quot;&gt;Simple Restaurant Reservations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ticketbase for Restaurants (in terms of UI/UX). Instead of selling tickets, it takes reservations for restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cyclonesign&quot;&gt;Cyclonesign&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;a href=&quot;http://stormpulse.com&quot;&gt;Stormpulse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://riskpulse.com&quot;&gt;Riskpulse&lt;/a&gt;, but bringing it in the Philippines. The Philippines gets hit with over 20 storms per year, we lose a lot of money because of this. Enables companies to be at the same level of proactiveness as PAGASA and government agencies. Plot out your physical assets and routes in the Philippines using a map, set alerts for wind levels and temperature, person in-charge/cargo drivers gets SMS warnings when something reaches the threshold. B2B model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Status: I developed large parts of this for a long time. Indexed and scraped a truckload of data from various international and national government weather sites. Wasn’t a fan of private API’s, government data for storms were more accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;report-for-tasks-done-self-hosted-idonethishttpsidonethiscom&quot;&gt;Report For Tasks Done: Self-hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://idonethis.com/&quot;&gt;iDoneThis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple Team Performance Management in contrast of Project Management. Twitter/Dribbble like experience asking you about what you worked and what you accomplished on. You can only post once a day. Automatically builds a view of what your entire team has accomplished during a project using these tweets. Celebrate small wins and keep morale up. You can also get what you’ve accomplished during your tenure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minutes-of-the-meeting-markup&quot;&gt;Minutes of the Meeting markup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in the environment where I sometimes get to be faced with clients. I want to have a markup similar as Markdown, but specifically targetting the minutes of the meeting. More attention to the meeting, less attention to writing it all down and formatting it. Write Frontmatter, write it in a specified format, enter something in your command line, and it gets sent to all the contacts in the Frontmatter. Complete with actionable items and main highlights of the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;services&quot;&gt;Services&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;uber-for-house-services&quot;&gt;Uber for House Services&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a plumbing problem? Snap a photo, make a few descriptions, select “Plumbing Service”, Service providers try to bid on it. It’s essentially a mobile application where you can easily get services for your home. Fortunately gawin.ph is a prime example of this, and I’m excited to try them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creative-services-friends&quot;&gt;Creative Services Friends&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Need a hip hop dance instructor? An events host? An graphic artist? A videographer? A photographer? An events coordinator? Baker? Acting coach? My group of friends offer these services. The app allows you to easily get their services. Just like ‘Uber for House Services’, but this targets creatives. The value? Curation. The app can be used to set up your own “Creative Services Group” with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s it, I’ll keep updating this very same list. I’ll probably permalink this in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://acesubido.com/about&quot;&gt;“about/contact”&lt;/a&gt; page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q: Hey some of these are great! Wouldn’t someone steal these? Why would you give that away?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some good reads:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LechKaniuk/status/683811288842133505&quot;&gt;You should be more afraid if no one wants to copy you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10944972&quot;&gt;“Idea’s are like blank books. Unless you have passion for the idea, you are not going to fill in the 400 blank pages with the details.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-1-blog-series/ideas-are-cheap-execution-is-worth-millions-e203efbcaa49&quot;&gt;Idea’s are cheap, execution is worth millions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“It’s a disease to think that a great idea is 90 percent of the work. The problem with that is that there’s just a tremendous amount of craftsmanship in between a great idea and a great product” - Steve Jobs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Facebook, Google+, MySpace, Friendster, Orkut all had the same idea. But execution and design is what matters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=10942823&quot;&gt;it’s been two years now, and nobody has stolen any of the ideas. It could just be that my ideas suck, but I suspect that the worry of people stealing ideas is nothing to worry about for any of us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To be honest, each one of these ideas takes about 5-10 years of passion to perfectly execute it. At which point, either it stays true throughout or evolves into something totally different. I only have one lifetime and I won’t have time to take on every one of these things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the idea of “stealing” is a “pessimists” view. Viewing this in an optimistic perspective, I may actually get in contact with people who definitely need someone to technically implement any of these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2016/01/21/my-useful-secret-projects-and-business-ideas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2016/01/21/my-useful-secret-projects-and-business-ideas.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How can executives/business guys &#39;appreciate&#39; Big Data?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I get that question from some of my officemates. How can people appreciate “Big Data Technologies”. Is there a demo to make people appreciate “Big Data” or “Hadoop”? How can we sell “Data Lakes vs Data Warehouses”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s hard to appreciate a piece of technology without knowing what pain it actually solves. Hadoop solves the pain of computing by presenting this conventional way of doing Distributed Computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the term “Big Data” is being passed around too much, it’s getting too abstracted. We need to get a little lower down the chain, closer to real things and tasks entailing “doing Big Data”. As I said before, I feel that “Big Data” is a marketing term thrown for problems/solutions revolving around “Distributed Computing and Storage”, much like how “Cloud” is for “Remote Servers, Services and Applications”. At the tip of these solutions is something called Hadoop. Now, Hadoop is more of a framework, accompanied with a set of libraries to implement that framework. At the current state of the software industry, there’s no single piece of technology that magically translates your data into wonderful visualizations and actionable insights that’s instantly aligned to making your business more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People have been blinded by technology. We’re so impressed by “Big Data” and all these buzzwords revolving around technology. We forget that technology isn’t meant to replace humans and how we process information, but it was made to complement us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The other buzzword that epitomizes a bias toward substitution is “big data”. Today’s companies have an insatiable appetite for data, mistakenly believeing that more data always creates more value. But big data is usually dumb data. Computers can find patterns that elude humans, but they don’t know how to compare patterns from different sources or how to interpret complex behaviors. Actionable insights can only come from a human analyst (or the kind of generalized artifical intelligence that exists only in science fiction).&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We have let ourselves become enchanted by big data only because we exoticize technology. We’re impressed with small feats accomplished by computers alone but we ignore achievements from complementarity because the human contribution makes them less uncanny.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Peter Thiel (Founder of Paypal and Palantir), from “Zero To One”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big Data technologies such as Hadoop, HBase, NiFi, Tableau and Spark are tools for Developers and Analysts to make their lives easier. It makes it easier for them to crunch numbers, transform data, and other stuff to make those charts and visualizations the business guys are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s hard to sell them to business guys as some sort of “magic box”. There’s no “demo” where they can instantly “appreciate it” without human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s like saying “How can executives/business guys ‘appreciate’ Ruby on Rails?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to sell that to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demos with fancy charts won’t work on most business guys: “Hey, our current IT Team can do that with their databases and BI tools. What’s new?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, “how can executive/business guys ‘appreciate’ Big Data?”. Take this with a grain of salt though, I’m not a biz dev guy: Sell it to their VP of Engineering, their developers, their technical team. Naturally they’ll build great apps and dashboards on top of it. It’ll sell itself to the rest of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: My thoughts written here are not of my employers. These are solely my opinions and they’re not tied to what AGSX stands for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2016/01/21/how-can-executives-appreciate-big-data-technologies.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2016/01/21/how-can-executives-appreciate-big-data-technologies.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where to invest my money? I&#39;m 17 years old ....</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m 17 years old (turning 18 on August, 2016), i’m still studying college (my 1st year) and at the same time, doing freelance designing. I earn 20-30k php per month sa designs ko. So far so good naman, kayang i-balance ang study at freelance work.
Been doing this since 2012, thanks to my designs, i was able to buy things i want and i need. Now comes a point na halos ok na ko sa mga meron ako, and iniisip ko kung paano ko ma-save ang pera ko. Wala naman ako alam sa mga investments/stocks/etc dahil ang course ko ay Multimedia Arts. Tried searching online about sa stock market but i dont think i have the knowledge para pasukin yun.
What’s the best way para ma-save ko ang money ko at hindi ako bili ng bili ng mga not-so-important stuff? I don’t want to be broke when i grow up, so i want to save these money :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put together a handy-dandy handbook/guide for you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, before anything, remove all debt. Zero out your credit card balance on the things you just bought. “Financial freedom” is only attained when you have no debt. Someone who nets 20-30K PHP per month but doesn’t have debt, has more “financial freedom” than someone who nets 150K PHP yet has a large chunk of debt and lives under stress of knowing they owe someone money.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Second, change your mindset in purchases. The best way to save your money is not some list of things to do, but rather, a radical change of mindset: don’t let material possessions define your identity. Define “need to have” and “nice to have”. Ask yourself “what do I value?” whenever you feel you’re about to purchase something stupid. Do you really need a moleskine for mockups? Is buying another cup of Starbucks really that important? Do I really need a new pair of shoes? Get your parents to help you in this. Another set of eyes definitely helps. You’re young, so don’t worry about getting broke and spending your savings, worry about what you’re actually spending your money on.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Third, is the most important one, if you do this and #2, you can easily get #4: Change your mindset on the word “investment”. Money is a device to exchange value, it is not a source of wealth, it will run out on you. So, technically, the best “investment” is putting more money on what currently earns you money: your skill. Buy a book from a famous designer, attend FFC, engage the design community and the market, spend more money/time experimenting and working on your own project, instead of doing something else. This mindset will increase how much you earn in amounts that you will not foresee.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I do this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Think of a rich person, one who gained their riches from great skill. If you took away their “businesses”, “investments” and “savings”, they probably won’t have a problem. Sure they’ll get hurt badly, but they can recover from a bankruptcy. The reason is because they’ve invested highly in themselves and are highly skilled. With their skill, they’ve attained a good professional network and they can easily recover from brutal bankruptcies. Their “investments” (stocks/mutual funds/etc.) are just overflow, fruits, of their true investment: their skill.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;On the opposite, research about lottery winners who ironically got bankrupted. Take note: some of them even had “funds and investments”.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you ever got broke, you can confidently get back up due to reputation, discipline in purchases and skill.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fourth, the only time you “invest” or pour money into “investments/funds”, is when income is already overflowing against your expenses. The best gauge for that is when you’ve 1) attained the usual “3-6 months of income as savings” and 2) at least being able to save more than 30-50% of your monthly net. A well-maintained bank account is a sign of debtlessness, discipline in purchases, and overflow. This makes you liquid, allowing you to shift wealth to where you need it (emergencies, travel, skill investment, etc.). It’s the reason why a lot of people over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/personalfinance&quot;&gt;/r/personalfinance&lt;/a&gt; suggests to work on a savings account first.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fifth, after you’ve changed your mindset, proven you can manage your finances with a good bank account, then you can get your hands dirty with “investments” while improving your skill:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Get medical insurance first, your parents will jump for joy when you get this for yourself. Head over to Blue Cross or Medicard. Basic medical coverage from Medicard hover around 8.9K PHP/year (700PHP~ per month).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Get life insurance that also doubles as an investment fund (SunLife is a safe bet, PruLife has nice offerings that has medical coverage infused with it).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lastly, pick an Index Fund. BPI offers the Philippine Equity Index Fund. BDO has this as well. Whichever you like, they both perform very well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ano yung Index Fund?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In much simpler terms: Ever see a picture or a huge chart in the business/finance section of a media website or a newspaper? The one that says “Philippine Stock Exchange Composite Index”? An Index Fund tries to closely follow those numbers. In laymans terms: You give money to a company, say BPI. The company would have fund managers that pick and trade stocks which closely matches the companies in that huge chart. So, when you see that the “Philippine Stock Exchange Composite Index” went up by 2% in one month, you can safely assume that the money you placed in BPI went up at about 1.25%-1.5% for that month as well.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ang daming mga iba pang funds diba? Why an Index Fund? Why not a mutual fund or treasury bills? Ano difference nila?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’ll explain as simple as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Treasury bills are government-based. You give the government money, they turn it into government projects which earns them money, which they use to pay you back with interest. T-bills as they call it are for the paranoid; they’re ultra-safe. Unless the Senate voted to turn itself into a strip club and Malacanang is burning with gasoline, your money is safe from anything else in the world. Besides if it came to that, money might not be important anymore in the Philippines anyway; you’d have to rely on your skill to live or learn farming to feed yourself. However, with the safety, comes a huge cost (minimum is 200K on PNB, returns per year are very small, expect a 10-20 year return)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mutual funds are a pool of money from different people: they hire a professional stock broker or fund manager which trades for them. Mutual funds have higher transaction fees than Index Funds. From a personal experience, only a few mutual funds/companies have beaten or come close to the Index, and the really good ones are pretty expensive and complicated to enter into.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, again, why an Index Fund?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A NYTimes article called the American-based “Vanguard Index Fund” as the “bread-and-butter index fund for the individual”. Index Funds are a gateway to the stock market and opens up your mind about it. It’s “the vanilla ice cream of finance”. They have low transaction fees, they’re easy to understand, doesn’t require much commitment and as “passive” as you make it. They’re not as safe though, when a “market crash” happens, everyone gets pulled down, especially Index Funds. Don’t worry; what goes down usually goes back up, people usually get great returns from Index funds when they hold them for 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you’re not earning millions per year and just starting out on investments, this is your go to.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;BPI Express Online and BDO Online Banking integrates tightly with their index funds. You can easily top up and cash out straight from/to your bank account.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On picking and trading stocks.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;It actively requires “skill”. Picking and trading stocks is a skillset to be learned. You have to be up to date, and you need to pick your companies well and do your research on them. If you really want to improve on that skill, head over to COL Financial to get a grasp of things. It doesn’t matter if COL is good/not-good based on the opinion of other people, what matters is you get started.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Personally I don’t advise this path, unless you really want to build a career as a really good trader. You’re already good at design, so don’t lose focus.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Few reminders: Don’t get arrogant. Don’t be in a hurry to make more money. Don’t be in a hurry. Period. Take time to get better with your work, don’t rush it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/11/14/where-to-invest-my-money-i-m-17-years-old.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/11/14/where-to-invest-my-money-i-m-17-years-old.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is a Real Time Analytics Platform?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few weeks/months since I’ve been plunged into this “Big Data” ecosystem, all I could sense was that
“Big Data” is a marketing term for problems that require “Distributed Frameworks” as solutions, much like how “Cloud” is a marketing term for how “Remote Servers” are provisioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve heard the word “Real Time Analytics Platform” thrown around a lot, but what does that really mean? What is that anyway? What is Real Time Analytics? And what is a Real Time Analytics Platform?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think people forgot it’s meaning as time passes by, so let’s get down to what it really means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Time Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakdown: Analytics is the discovery of meaningful patterns in data. Real Time adds “immediacy”. The combination of both means that “Real Time Analytics” is discovering meaningful patterns in data for something urgent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Outage map for a utility company that is updated immediately&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Target push at customers on geofence detection for retail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fraud detection systems for finance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emergencies such as forest fires and emergency call recordings for government owned utilities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social program fraud detection for government agencies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log analysis for bad patterns in high-tech companies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anonymised usage patterns for telco’s (if they want to sell it as data or use for internal analytics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some example use cases that are urgent and require immediate attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create an environment where you can do “Real Time Analytics”, you’d need to safely work with 3 aspects of how your data flows into your system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Input - an event happens (new sale, new customer, someone enters a geofence, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Process and Store Input - capture the data of the event, and analyze the data without leveraging resources that are dedicated to operations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Output - consume this data without disturbing operations (reports, dashboard, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2nd and 3rd bullet is very important. It requires extensive use of background processes to achieve low-latency and high throughput to provide real time characteristics. In programming, we’ve all been taught to put really expensive operations behind another process/thread  (Resque/Sidekiq, micro-services architecture) instead of blocking everything until the operation is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like a normal controller class in a web app, it’s not that complex and handling this won’t be a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then again, let’s take for example, a typical megacorporation. They’d procured the usual .NET/Oracle/SAP stack (as much as possible, no cloud, they’re following some sort of security protocol).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To provide “Real Time Analytics”, usually they’d have a plethora of ETL Background Processes/Workers with Excel/DB integrations, per department, running on any number of servers, each having their own fault-tolerance and scaling strategies. If the data requirements change, they’d have to go through this set of intertwined systems and change each one of them, make sure they don’t crash and push the changes back to production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A normal controller class won’t cut it anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Time Analytics Platform&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our sample megacorporation, that current mosaic of stuff is their “Real Time Analytics Platform”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, that setup will not help. It’s not real-time unless it happens instantly!” - just to sidetrack a little bit; this actually won’t happen. Many multi-department companies want to achieve that vague finish line called “Real Time Analytics” with a “Single Customer View” inside a room with a lot of screens displaying tons of dashboards. You got to define those things clearly first to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latency is as low as we can make it, but it’s not just the speed, it’s also the extensibility where you can easily change those set of intertwined systems based on requirements, which would probably change a lot during such a big undertaking. All departments should be together to work on this, or else it won’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s a great team at the megacorp; chances are, they’ll use bits and pieces of frameworks here and there instead of having a mosaic of stuff to help you get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, they’ll be reinventing a set of rules and guiding principles on code; how to scale, fault-tolerance, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’ll be reinventing a framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard enough to get great people to work with, but it’s harder if they’re working on this mosaic of apps that doesn’t have a solid framework. There are many good frameworks lying around, so learn the frameworks and leverage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, the frameworks that help blot out bullet point #2 are what people sell as “Real Time Analytics Platform”’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PS: So, what’s a good one?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I won’t endorse anything. Acquiring something that would solve something complex without knowing what really needs to be done will end badly. Ask the tech team first, they’d probably know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/10/24/what-is-a-real-time-analytics-platform.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/10/24/what-is-a-real-time-analytics-platform.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>header navigation screenshot of a cryptocurrency</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nv6v605ZXo1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nv6v605ZXo1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Header navigation screenshot of a Cryptocurrency Job Board I made with a friend. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played with Black and Gold to bring out the feel of &amp;ldquo;premium&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;luxury&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t over-design and add gratitious animations or transitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built it with Rails :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:01:12 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>finally got around to launch the family business</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nsy3e6me0V1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nsy3e6me0V1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to launch the family business website. Here&amp;rsquo;s a shot of content above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 09:13:18 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/08/12/finally-got-around-to-launch-the-family-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/08/12/finally-got-around-to-launch-the-family-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making a home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at &amp;ldquo;house and lot&amp;rdquo; real estate around the Metro. At most, the figure floating in our heads is around 8M-9M PHP. To loan that amount to a bank and to pay it off for 20 years I have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have Annual 2.4M PHP Income (Around 160k PHP Monthly Income)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay 48,500 PHP in 20 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a big number to hit, and to be honest, I get overwhelmed by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am reminded of one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiming to &amp;ldquo;build a house&amp;rdquo; between &amp;ldquo;making a home&amp;rdquo; are two different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping that in mind, strive to make happy memories instead of zoning out for the next 5-10 years trying to make more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiously waiting to hit your financial goals, looking forward to pay days and stressing out to make more money will not &amp;ldquo;make a home&amp;rdquo;. The only memories you&amp;rsquo;ll imprint on your wife and children will be of a man who always arrived home thinking of business and cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Building a house&amp;rdquo; is only part of &amp;ldquo;making a home&amp;rdquo;, not the other way around. Ask God to help you balance the emotions out, you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to ask Him for money. Have faith, He basically got your back already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He already got you married right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:08 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/08/03/making-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/08/03/making-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Practice is the key to getting better at everything. Ignore the concept of innate talent or gift. People who are good are good because they spent a lot of time practicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who practice a lot usually do so because they’re interested in it. It’s not hard or homework for them. If there’s a gift, it’s the gift of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists copy a lot. They don’t come up with stuff clear out of their heads. They look at a lot of things, keep a lot of references, and blend ideas together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who are famous are so not because they’re good, but because they’ve worked hard to become famous. It was important to them, so they did what it took to become famous. Being good at something is a small part of that, small enough that famous people aren’t usually all that good. Their time was better spent becoming famous. (This is the biggest lesson from this list. It basically implies that you can ignore people who have blogs and podcasts. Seek out the unknown experts in your field.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t make decisions based on money. Don’t stay at a job because the shares might be worth something, or because the company might get acquired. These things rarely happen and you can’t get your time back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is totally winging it all the time. Confident people are just better at hiding it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9092456&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;— lkesteloot&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9092246&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 13:13:28 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-do-you-wish-you-had-known-before-you-turned.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-do-you-wish-you-had-known-before-you-turned.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;What is your stack?&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails, and all the Ruby ecosystem has to offer, coupled with Postgres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a project becomes even more complicated and it looks as if Rails with Resque/Sidekiq won&amp;rsquo;t cut it, I go with what we (team on any project) all decide to use for certain parts of the stack. Whether that be Ember/Backbone/Angular on the front or Scala/Go for certain workers, Debian or CentOS on the server, etc. or what not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal preference won&amp;rsquo;t mean anything if a project goes bigger than me. I value working with other people over technology choices, even if the collectively-decided pieces of the stack were a little different from my own stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9122381&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Discussion on HackerNews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 12:49:57 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-is-your-stack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-is-your-stack.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsive Centered Bootstrap Columns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I see this being repeated over-and-over again to create centered content with bootstrap columns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; .container
   .row
     .col-md-offset-3.col-md-6
       Centered Column
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving you only to work with even-numbered columns for perfectly centered content inside a bootstrap column:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; .col-md-offset-2.col-md-8
 .col-md-offset-3.col-md-6
 .col-md-offset-4.col-md-4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foundation has built-in centered columns, so here&amp;rsquo;s a way to create centered bootstrap columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; // SCSS
 .col-center {
   float: none;
   margin-right: auto;
   margin-left: auto;
 }

 // HAML
 .container
    .row
       .col-md-5.col-center
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see this in action, just take a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ace-subido/pen/MYVNBv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: this works with Bootstrap 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 12:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/21/responsive-centered-bootstrap-columns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/21/responsive-centered-bootstrap-columns.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
