<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>acesubido</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://acesubido.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://acesubido.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 23:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 23:21:38 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>header navigation screenshot of a cryptocurrency</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nv6v605ZXo1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nv6v605ZXo1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Header navigation screenshot of a Cryptocurrency Job Board I made with a friend. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played with Black and Gold to bring out the feel of &amp;ldquo;premium&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;luxury&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t over-design and add gratitious animations or transitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built it with Rails :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:01:12 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/09/25/header-navigation-screenshot-of-a-cryptocurrency.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>finally got around to launch the family business</title>
        <description>&lt;a href=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nsy3e6me0V1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/tumblr_files/tumblr_nsy3e6me0V1rxgz1ko1_1280.png&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to launch the family business website. Here&amp;rsquo;s a shot of content above the fold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 09:13:18 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/08/12/finally-got-around-to-launch-the-family-business.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/08/12/finally-got-around-to-launch-the-family-business.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Making a home</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at &amp;ldquo;house and lot&amp;rdquo; real estate around the Metro. At most, the figure floating in our heads is around 8M-9M PHP. To loan that amount to a bank and to pay it off for 20 years I have to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have Annual 2.4M PHP Income (Around 160k PHP Monthly Income)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay 48,500 PHP in 20 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a big number to hit, and to be honest, I get overwhelmed by it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I am reminded of one thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aiming to &amp;ldquo;build a house&amp;rdquo; between &amp;ldquo;making a home&amp;rdquo; are two different things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping that in mind, strive to make happy memories instead of zoning out for the next 5-10 years trying to make more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anxiously waiting to hit your financial goals, looking forward to pay days and stressing out to make more money will not &amp;ldquo;make a home&amp;rdquo;. The only memories you&amp;rsquo;ll imprint on your wife and children will be of a man who always arrived home thinking of business and cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Building a house&amp;rdquo; is only part of &amp;ldquo;making a home&amp;rdquo;, not the other way around. Ask God to help you balance the emotions out, you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to ask Him for money. Have faith, He basically got your back already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He already got you married right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:00:08 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/08/03/making-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/08/03/making-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?&lt;/blockquote&gt;&amp;#8212;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Practice is the key to getting better at everything. Ignore the concept of innate talent or gift. People who are good are good because they spent a lot of time practicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who practice a lot usually do so because they’re interested in it. It’s not hard or homework for them. If there’s a gift, it’s the gift of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artists copy a lot. They don’t come up with stuff clear out of their heads. They look at a lot of things, keep a lot of references, and blend ideas together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people who are famous are so not because they’re good, but because they’ve worked hard to become famous. It was important to them, so they did what it took to become famous. Being good at something is a small part of that, small enough that famous people aren’t usually all that good. Their time was better spent becoming famous. (This is the biggest lesson from this list. It basically implies that you can ignore people who have blogs and podcasts. Seek out the unknown experts in your field.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t make decisions based on money. Don’t stay at a job because the shares might be worth something, or because the company might get acquired. These things rarely happen and you can’t get your time back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone is totally winging it all the time. Confident people are just better at hiding it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9092456&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;— lkesteloot&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9092246&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;What do you wish you had known before you turned 40?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 13:13:28 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-do-you-wish-you-had-known-before-you-turned.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-do-you-wish-you-had-known-before-you-turned.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>&quot;What is your stack?&quot;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rails, and all the Ruby ecosystem has to offer, coupled with Postgres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a project becomes even more complicated and it looks as if Rails with Resque/Sidekiq won&amp;rsquo;t cut it, I go with what we (team on any project) all decide to use for certain parts of the stack. Whether that be Ember/Backbone/Angular on the front or Scala/Go for certain workers, Debian or CentOS on the server, etc. or what not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal preference won&amp;rsquo;t mean anything if a project goes bigger than me. I value working with other people over technology choices, even if the collectively-decided pieces of the stack were a little different from my own stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9122381&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Discussion on HackerNews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2015 12:49:57 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-is-your-stack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/28/what-is-your-stack.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsive Centered Bootstrap Columns</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I see this being repeated over-and-over again to create centered content with bootstrap columns:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; .container
   .row
     .col-md-offset-3.col-md-6
       Centered Column
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving you only to work with even-numbered columns for perfectly centered content inside a bootstrap column:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; .col-md-offset-2.col-md-8
 .col-md-offset-3.col-md-6
 .col-md-offset-4.col-md-4
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foundation has built-in centered columns, so here&amp;rsquo;s a way to create centered bootstrap columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; // SCSS
 .col-center {
   float: none;
   margin-right: auto;
   margin-left: auto;
 }

 // HAML
 .container
    .row
       .col-md-5.col-center
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see this in action, just take a look &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ace-subido/pen/MYVNBv&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: this works with Bootstrap 3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 12:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/02/21/responsive-centered-bootstrap-columns.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/02/21/responsive-centered-bootstrap-columns.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The numbers in our bank accounts are nothing more than a reflection, stop staring at them, focus on where the numbers came from instead.</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;The numbers in our bank accounts are nothing more than a reflection, stop staring at them, focus on where the numbers came from instead.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&amp;#8212;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 12:11:55 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2015/01/02/the-numbers-in-our-bank-accounts-are-nothing-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2015/01/02/the-numbers-in-our-bank-accounts-are-nothing-more.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stargazing in Manila: How, Where, When, Who</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love the actuality of space. The thought that if you go up high enough, there&amp;rsquo;s a vast expanse beyond the sky. Back then, as a kid, this was the cause for majority of my daydreaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered the time in my high school where our teacher arranged for a stargazing session. It was an all-nighter thing with the entire science club. The only thing in my recollection; it was the first time I saw a planet right in front of my eyes. Not those planets you see in textbooks, the one rendered by artists, but a real one, as real as the pencil you have in your hand. It&amp;rsquo;s just there, reflected on a piece of glass attached to a telescope. The thought of space is amazing, but seeing that right there before my eyes blew my 14-year old mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I also recollected: it was the PAGASA UP Observatory in Diliman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One night back in 2012, I went there with my wife and 3 other friends :) Long story short, they all had fun :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No more long prose, here are some details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the number for that UP Observatory - 929-1237&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com.ph/maps/@14.6509404,121.0721939,19z?hl=en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;hellip;and a map to where it is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;annndddd also a picture of the building (credits for the photo goes to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pagasa.dost.gov.ph/astronomy/astronomy-in-the-philippines&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PAGASA&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;img src=&quot;http://38.media.tumblr.com/b7d4d8f45eb7158b88388d467c2520f8/tumblr_inline_nfsllkRlFG1rqf6g8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upon calling the number, ask if they can accommodate you and if the place is not busy for the night. If it&amp;rsquo;s not busy, ask for the forecast before you go there, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go there all excited only to find out no planets are visible and the skies aren&amp;rsquo;t clear. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember you can&amp;rsquo;t book the &amp;ldquo;viewing of the cosmos&amp;rdquo; in advance like some special food in your favourite restaurant. You&amp;rsquo;re just hoping that most of the things you want to see are there and the skies are clear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depending on the planets you want to see, be prepared for an all-nighter, Go there after 7pm or 8pm, prepare to stay up as late as 2am depending on the things you want to view. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We brought food, water, stayed in our cars, listened to music, cleaned up after ourselves and kept quiet to pay respect to the place. Noisy and rowdy people will probably get a lot of unwanted attention from the campus security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can rent their telescopes, if I recall correctly, you can rent each for below 50PHP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask nicely, you&amp;rsquo;ll get help from them in finding a planet. Trust me, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t handled a telescope before, they&amp;rsquo;re hard to find.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The planets are moving targets since the earth is rotating, they&amp;rsquo;re smaller than a grain of sand compared to the entire expanse of the sky.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The PAGASA staff that was helping us out even gave us a friendly challenge to find the moon. It&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as we all thought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I offered to pay them extra because seriously, the experience is worth more than 20PHP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here&amp;rsquo;s a shot of the moon from my wife&amp;rsquo;s iPhone4s pointed directly at the viewfinder of a telescope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/e67bc75a0d7fbd96892000875501f75b/tumblr_inline_nfsmgaLN1d1rqf6g8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 17:09:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2014/11/29/stargazing-in-manila-how-where-when-who.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2014/11/29/stargazing-in-manila-how-where-when-who.html</guid>
        
        <category>personal</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aliens Sentry Gun UI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a scene in the movie Aliens (1984) where the suspense was building up due to the impending fact that a large pack of extra-terrestrial man-slayers were coming to give the heroes a lot of violent hugs and brutal kisses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the Colonial Marines set up 2 sentry guns to shoot them all down from the safety of another room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;365&quot; style=&quot;margin: 20px 0;&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/HQDy-5IQvuU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny how the user interface for the sentry gun adds to the build-up of suspense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://33.media.tumblr.com/ec38f12ec55e3aaa4ffe5e412321fac4/tumblr_inline_nfqyygHMqM1rqf6g8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one good example of effective user interface design. Simple, understandable and obviously usable. No moving particles or random neon boxes popping around the screen. When you look at it, it seems though you could easily set up a sentry gun for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just got reminded by a 40-year old movie to design effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2014 19:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2014/11/28/aliens-sentry-gun-ui.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2014/11/28/aliens-sentry-gun-ui.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On building side projects</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Think of your scope. Now cut it in half. Halve it once more. There, start with that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 08:12:52 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://acesubido.com/2014/11/14/on-building-side-projects.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://acesubido.com/2014/11/14/on-building-side-projects.html</guid>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
